准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
闪光的珍宝
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
编剧
技术总监
动画总监
制片指导
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
蟹堡王
来份怪物蟹黄堡
One Monster Krabby Patty, please
此处点餐
好久没人点怪物蟹黄堡了
No one's ordered a Monster Patty in ages
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
一份怪物蟹黄堡
One Monster Krabby Patty
你是不是说了怪物蟹黄堡
D-d-did you say a M-Monster Krabby Patty?
一份怪物蟹黄堡
One Monster Krabby Patty
怪物蟹黄堡
Monster Krabby Patty?
我的海神王啊
Oh, dear Neptune
老天爷啊
Oh, boy
我们能成的
We can do this
数到三  就翻面
At the count of three, we flip
好了吗
Ready?
一
One
二
two
三
three
铲铲
Spat?
继续
Go on
最好还是继续工作吧
Well, we'd better get back to work
工作
Work?
这还怎么继续工作  明明都没了
How could I go back to work without
明明没了铲铲
without Spat?
换个别的锅铲用
Use another spatula
什么
What?
我能用的只有一把锅铲
There is only one spatula for me
那就是铲铲
and that is Spat
铲铲  等等我
Spat, wait up
铲铲
Spat
我来了  铲铲
I'm coming, Spat
急诊
铲铲
Oh, Spat
我们在一起经历了这么多
We've been through so much together
这真的很难说出口
There's no easy way to say this
海绵宝宝  如果我是你的话
SpongeBob, if I were you
就会认真开始考虑
I would give serious consideration
to start thinking about
换把新锅铲
a replacement spatula
回去吧  休息一下
Go home, get some rest
我们会
We'll
尽己所能的
try to do everything we can
谢谢医生
Thank you, Doctor
我才不是医生
I'm not a doctor
我只是个在找合适角色的演员
I'm an actor researching for a role
好
Yes
我就快领到这段的戏份了
I am so totally gonna get this part
换把新锅铲
Replacement spatula?
怎么可能会有东西能换
How could anything ever replace
快看那
Look at that
阿铲在内
看起来好高贵
Looks fancy
好闪亮
So shiny
这线条  好有
Those lines, so
光泽
sleek
我在说什么鬼话
What am I talking about?
我用不着这玩意
I don't need this
可能确实需要
Maybe I do need this
我就会认真考虑
I would give serious consideration to
换把新锅铲
a replacement spatula
不准摸阿铲
No touchy-touchy the Le Spatula
阿铲特别特别的贵
It's very, very expensive
对不起
I'm sorry
当然  如果你买下这个上品物件
Of course, if you purchase this fine item
就可以
you may
拿着它
hold it
我口袋里有一点零钱
Well, I've got some loose change in my pocket
这些够付吗
Will this cover it?
不够
No
那现在呢
How about now?
不够
No
现在呢
Now?
不够
No
现在呢
Now?
不够
No
现在呢
Now?
不够
No
现在呢
Now?
不够
No
现在呢
Now?
不够
No
裤头村房产
售出
我所有家当就这么多了
That's everything I have
我现在可以买阿铲了吗
Now can I buy Le Spatula?
所有家当是吧
Everything, huh?
衣服不错
Nice outfit
傍晩好  先生
Good evening, sir
老奶奶好  你最近如何
Hey, Granny, what's shakin'?
今天有点风
Breezy today
衣服不错  海绵宝宝
Nice outfit, SpongeBob
谢谢了  章鱼哥
Thanks, Squidward
钱花得很值
It was worth every penny
你干嘛在浪费时间
What's all the lollygagging about?
蟹老板  快去看海绵宝宝
Mr. Krabs, get a load of SpongeBob
最好是什么好事
This better be good
大家马上就会知晓你的美丽了
Soon everyone will know of your beauty
阿铲
行了  里面是怎
All right, what's going on in
你难道连一点羞耻心都没有吗  小子
Don't you have any shame, boy?
我的羞耻心都到这里面去了  蟹老板
All my shame went in here, Mr. Krabs
阿铲
Le Spa-tu-ler
这到底是什么玩意
What in blazes isthat?
可以解决我工作的一点小难题
Just the answer to our little production dilemma
那这玩意能干啥
Well, what can it do?
能让我变出名吗
Can it make me famous?
不仅应有尽有  还不止呢
Anything you want and more
好刺激的样子
That sounds exciting
我来试试看
Let me have a go at it
对不起  蟹老板
I'm sorry, Mr. Krabs
我不能给你
no can do
什么
What?
你这是要跟你老板唱反调吗
Are you going against your commanding officer?
不是这样的
No, it's not that
这可是超级高科技产品
It's just that
this is a highly developed piece of engineering
想掌握它得慢慢来
that takes quality time to master
既然你有了这个花哨机器  那你最好
With that fancy machinery, I expect you
让做蟹黄堡的速度给我翻倍
to make Krabby Patties twice as fast
这应该不成问题  蟹老板
I don't think that'll be a problem, Mr. Krabs
其实
In fact
阿铲3000为您服务
Le Spatula 3000, at your service
厉害
Impressive
倒要看它能不能再让我大开眼界一回
Well, let's see that thing impress me even more--
给我招呼更多客人
by bringing in more customers
往我腰包多塞一点钱
and more money in me pocket
阿铲的能力一定会让你难以置信
You won't believe what Le Spatula is capable of
准备好大显神威没
Ready to show 'em, buddy?
没事的  没必要这么害羞
It's okay, no need to be shy
上班第一天都比较难受
It's always tough the first day on the job
我能来一份蟹黄堡吗
Can I get one Krabby Patty, please?
海绵宝宝  来一份蟹黄堡
SpongeBob, I need one Krabby Patty
一份蟹黄堡  马上就来
One Krabby Patty coming up lickety-split
有什么问题吗  阿铲兄弟
Spat, is there something wrong, pal?
我碰不得垃圾食物  就比如这种
I would not dare touch such slop as this
你怎么说来着
how you say
蟹黄堡
Krabby Patty
我生来就是制作顶级菜肴的
I am designed for the utmost in culinary cuisine
岂有此理
No less
可是
But
可我们应该是朋友的啊
but I thought we were friends
跟你做朋友
Friends with you?
我们甚至都不在同一个社会阶层里
We are not even in the same social class
享受你平庸的一生吧  煎炸厨师
Have a nice life of mediocrity, fry cook
阿铲  别走
Le Spatula, wait
我为你放弃了所有家当
I gave up everything for you
我们还是有感情的
We had something
这算哪门子感情
How's that for something?
永别了  俗人
Au revoir, peasant
祝你在这家小破餐馆打工愉快
Have fun ladling in your greasy spoon
怎么回事
What happened?
阿铲走了  蟹老板
My spatula's gone, Mr. Krabs
那你没了锅铲要怎么做蟹黄堡
But how are you gonna flip Krabby Patties
without a spatu-ler?
我从前有一把锅铲
I hada spatula once
一把真正的锅铲
a real spatula
与我同甘共苦
one that stood by me through thick and thin
与我面对油骨
through grease and gristle
而我却背叛了他的忠实
and I betrayed his loyalty
就像傻子一样
like a fool
我还是有点喜欢你的旧锅铲的
I always did like your old spatu-ler
它每次都能把工作做好
He got the job done right every time
说得对  蟹老板
You're right, Mr. Krabs
要以锅铲的行为来评判锅铲的好坏
The truemeasure of a good spatula is by his actions
不能以什么花哨铬合金跟按钮来评判
not by some fancy chrome and buttons
我必须回去找我的旧锅铲
I've got to find my old spatula
去找吧
Go to him
快去  小子
Go now, boy
趁着我客人还没跑光赶紧去
Go before I lose all me customers
铲铲
Spatula?
这不是真的
It can't be true
太晩了
It's too late
海绵宝宝  我
SpongeBob, I
我很遗憾要跟你说
I hate to tell you this
这我知道
I know
他现在已经到了天国的厨房抽屉里了
He's moved on to that big kitchen drawer in the sky
他
He's
逝去了
gone
其实我想说的不是这个
Actually, it's not that
我没有领到戏份
I didn't get the acting part
真是遗憾
I'm so sorry
顺带一提  这个不是你的锅铲
By the way, that's not your spatula
你兄弟已经在医院里被修好了
Your buddy's all patched up in the infirmary
医院
铲铲
Spatula
兄弟
Old buddy
我好高兴你康复了
I'm so glad you're better
铲铲  怎么了
Spatula, what's wrong?
可我不是要故意背叛你的
But I didn't mean to betray you
蟹老板需要替代品
Mr. Krabs needed a replacement
毕竟蟹黄堡肉饼不会自己翻自己
Krabby Patties don't flip themselves, you know
我那只是一时糊涂
It was a moment of weakness
对不起
I'm sorry
我都做了些什么
What have I done?
闪光的未必是金子
All that glitters is not gold
再见了  最好的朋友
Good-bye, best friend
蟹堡王
我再也找不到像他一样的锅铲了
I'll never find another spatula like him again
铲铲
Spatula?
你回来了
You're back
铲铲  既然我们又团圆了
Oh, Spatula, now that we're together again
任何一切都不会把我们分开
nothing will ever separate us
一份怪物蟹黄堡
One Monster Krabby Patty
兄弟  我们能成的
Okay, buddy, we can do this
好了没
Ready?
一
One
二
two
三
three
许愿井
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
编剧
技术总监
动画总监
制片指导
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
啥都没
Nothing
算了
Well
听起来好像有两毛五在大声呼救
That sounds like a quarter crying for help
快到爸爸这来
Come to papa
站在这别动  这位
Hold it right there, buddy
这两毛五是我儿子刚掉的
My son just dropped that quarter
是吗
Yeah?
我觉得那小孩看起来鬼鬼祟祟的
Well, that kid looks pretty shifty to me
他怕不会是偷的这两毛五吧
How do I know he didn't steal it?
那个小屁孩把好端端的钱给丢掉了
That little brat's throwing perfectly good money away
如果我弄不到钱  谁都不准
So if I can't have it, no one
希望他把你所有退休金都扔洞里去
I hope he throws all your retirement money down a hole
可怜的两毛五
Poor little quarter
怎么
What the?
这座井里全是钱
This well is full of money
放心好了  小家伙
Don't worry, little fellas
我会救你们的
I'll save you
不行
It's no use
我屁股太大了
Me poop deck's too big
许个愿吧  亲爱的
Make a wish, dear
我所有愿望都已经实现了
All my wishes have already come true
你啊
Oh, you
不要
No
我会来救你的  钱
I'll save you, money
救到了
Gotcha
你们这些没心没肺的畜生是在干什么
What do you heartless brutes think you're doing?
用许愿井
Using the wishing well
把硬币丢进去再许个愿
Well, you toss in a coin and make a wish
然后会怎样
And then what?
然后就没了
And that's it
没别的事了
Nothing else happens
可好玩了
It's fun
你们是说会有傻子把钱扔洞里玩吗
You mean suckers throw money down a hole for fun?
简直就是天大的骗局
That's the greatest scam ever
能把两毛五还回来了吗
Can we have our quarter back now?
蟹堡王
海绵宝宝  蟹黄堡怎么还没做好
SpongeBob, why aren't those patties ready?
完美不是催出来的
You can't rush perfection
我催的不是完美
I'm not rushing perfection
催的是你
I'm rushing you
你总是好会开玩笑  章鱼哥
Always the kidder, Squidward
这工作烂透了
This job stinks
不过至少我还没去挖什么水沟
But at least I'm not digging ditches
章鱼哥  海绵宝宝
Squidward SpongeBob
我有新工作要给你们做
I got a new job for you
X是标记点
X marks the spot
标记了尤金蟹纪念许愿井的位置
of the Eugene Krabs memorial wishing well
这边要挖许愿井
A wishing well, here?
不是必须先死了才能做纪念的玩意吗
Don't you have to be dead to have a memorial anything?
章鱼哥  难道你不相信魔法吗
Squidward, don't you believe in magic?
对啊  章鱼哥
Yeah, Squidward
你难道不相信魔法吗
don't you believe in magic?
我不信
No, I don't
蟹老板一样也不相信
And neither does Mr. Krabs
我反正相信
Well, I do
这座井会让好多梦想成真的
This well's gonna make a lot of dreams come true
你想要先许个什么愿望
What's the first thing you're gonna wish for?
能跟你离得越远越好
To be as far away from you as possible
海绵宝宝  这破洞可不会自己挖自己
Come on, SpongeBob, this hole's not gonna dig itself
我肯定也不去挖这个洞
And I'm certainly not gonna do it
章鱼哥  你激不激动
Squidward, aren't you excited?
这井肯定会帮上好多人的忙的
This is really gonna help people
拿上硬币还有魔力
Take a penny and some magic
哪怕生活悲惨无比
Even though your life is tragic
都能把梦想丢进井里
You can throw all your dreams down the well
哪怕每天痛苦难受
Although every day, the pain grows
彩虹之上骑独角兽
You'll ride unicorns on rainbows
把梦想丢进井里就能成
If you throw all your dreams down the well
此处点餐
每当你的生活即将崩溃
When your life's come apart at the seams
让你放弃你的所有梦想
And you've given up all your dreams
有了这些方法
Here is just the means
就能让梦想实现
To make those dreams come true
不再受苦  不再叹息
No more sufferin', no more sighin'
不再疼痛  不再哭泣
No more pain and no more cryin'
我才没哭
I'm not crying
把梦想丢进井里就能成
When you throw all your dreams down the well
开
章鱼哥  你觉得怎么样
Well, Squidward, what do you think?
刚刚那是我听过最难听的歌
That was the worst song I ever heard
不过至少这口破井挖完了
But at least this stupid well's finished
真是漂亮
It's beautiful
你们闻到了吗  小子
You smell that, boys?
是钱的味道
That's the smell of money
你想说的是不是魔法
You mean magic, don't you?
我能闻到的就只有那个垃圾箱
All I can smell is that Dumpster
章鱼哥  你可以回去收银了
All right, Squidward, you can go back to the register
只要没歌就成
As long as there's no singing
我跟蟹黄堡还有一场约会
And I've got a date with a Krabby Patty
先别走  海绵宝宝
Hold on there, SpongeBob
我先带你看看你的全新工作场所
Let me show you your new station
算是升职吧
It's kind of a promotion
升一点
Sort of
还有升职吗
A promotion?
我为什么要下到井里去
Why do I have to go down in the well?
要让你来收钱
To collect the money
我得待在这下面多久
How long do I have to stay down here?
八小时后见
See you in eight hours
谢谢让我升职
Thanks for the promotion
这里真的好黑好吓人
It sure is dark and scary in here
我好希望能有个高档望远镜
I sure wish I had a fancy telescope
能在海底用的望远镜
One that works underwater
这样就可以让我高兴得不得了了
That'd make me happier
than a june bug at a porch light sale
第一个愿望
Our very first wish
我等不及下一
I can't wait till it comes
我已经依照传统给你了一笔小钱
I have presented you
with a monetary offering, as custom dictates
我的愿望  又名命令
My wish, nay, my command
就是变高
is to be taller
一点点而已
Just a little
大到可以粉碎我的敌人
Just big enough to crush my enemies
消灭那些虫豸
like the vermin they are
天啊
Gosh
我希望能有辆漂亮新船
I wish I had a snazzy new boat
我想当个赛船辣妈
I want to be a hotrod mama
老天爷啊
Oh, my gosh
是谁说的话
Who said that?
派大星
Patrick
你怎么知道我名字的
How do you know my name?
派大星  这是座许愿井
Patrick, this is a wishing well
拿个硬币投进去许个愿就行
Just throw in a coin and make a wish
好吧  会说话的神奇垃圾桶
Okay, magical talking trashcan
我希望海绵宝宝能在这看看
I wish SpongeBob were here to see this
派大星
Patrick?
嗨  海绵宝宝
Hi, SpongeBob
我愿望实现了
I got my wish
派大星  你投币应该得先放手才行
Patrick, you're supposed to
let go of the coin when you throw it
反正我愿望实现了
But I got my wish
离我下班还有六个半小时
Well, we got six and a half hours till the end of my shift
你现在想干啥
What do you want to do now?
抓到了  你当鬼
Tag, you're it
海绵宝宝  你收获如何
SpongeBob, what kind of haul did you get?
可不错了  蟹老板
I did great, Mr. Krabs
有了珊迪的半毛钱
I got a nickel from Sandy
泡芙老师的两分钱
two pennies from Mrs. Puff
痞老板的一分钱
a penny from Plankton
还有副九成新的假牙
and this slightly used pair of dentures
我头朝下掉了下来
And I fell on my head
派大星或许可以卖掉几个钱
Well, I can probably get a couple of bucks for Patrick
算了
Nah
你最好把钱都交过来
You better just send up the money
修这许愿井的想法可真不错  蟹老板
This wishing well was a wonderful idea, Mr. Krabs
大家的愿望都成真了吗
Has anyone's wish come true yet?
还没
Not yet
不过我确定如果你有坚实的信心
But I'm sure, if you believe strong enough
挖得够深的话
and dug deep enough
大家的愿望就都会实现
everyone's wishes will come true
真的吗
Really?
真的没错  随便了
Yeah, sure, whatever
我们现在能出来了吗
Can we come out now?
老天爷啊  不行
Goodness, no
你必须要待在这下面
You gotta stay down there
以备大半夜有人来这许愿
just in case any late-night wishers come by
等天亮了我再来找你们
I'll be back for you at dawn
大家的愿望都没实现
No one's wishes are coming true
我们哪里做错了
What did we do wrong?
我知道我有坚实的信心
I know I believe hard enough
应该是我挖得不够深
Maybe I just didn't dig deep enough
你说怎么样  派大星
What do you say, Patrick?
准备好要挖魔法了吗
Are you ready to dig for some magic?
好了
Yeah
魔法已经消失不见
Oh, the magic has gone missin'
大家仍然还在许愿
And everyone's still wishin'
而他们的梦想都已然落空
But their dreams have fallen flat upon the ground
魔法就藏在石头下
You'll find magic under rubble
派大星  铲子快拿
So, Patrick, grab a shovel
魔法在这里就可以找到
And here is where the magic can be found
我们身处井底之下
We're at the bottom of a well
这样不是很好玩吗
But, man, won't it be swell
等我们让大家愿望都实现
When we make everyone's wishes all come true?
我的老天啊
Holy mackerel
派大星你看
Look, Patrick
魔法被我们碰见了
We've struck magic
这是好事吗
Is that good?
这是我除了当厨师之外
Next to being a fry cook
我所做的最重大的事情
it's the most important thing I've ever done
这是我唯一做过的事情
It's the only thing I've ever done
在这底下开不开心  海绵宝宝
Having fun down there, SpongeBob?
嗨  章鱼哥
Hi, Squidward
派大星居然也在这底下
Patrick's down there, too?
这好事真是越来越好了
It just gets better and better
你想要许个愿吗
Do you want to make a wish?
我愿望已经实现了
I got my wish
你们两个被困在了个黑暗的洞里
You two are stuck in a dark hole
还离我远远的
and away from me
章鱼哥  你猜怎么着
Guess what, Squidward?
我们找到魔法了
We found the magic
根本就没有魔法  海绵宝宝
There's no magic, SpongeBob
许愿井是专门用来骗你们这种傻子的
Wishing wells are just a scam to fool saps like you
不对  是真的
No, it's true
我们真的找到魔法了
We did find the magic
希望你能亲眼看见
I wish you could see it
章鱼哥  你想好要来参加派对了
Squidward, you decided to join the party
派对
Party
快让我出去
Let me outta here
我们才刚要玩点派对游戏呢
We were just gonna play some party games
抓到了  你当鬼
Tag, you're it
我一定要出去
I gotta get outta here
加油  章鱼哥
Go, Squidward
根本没办法爬出去
There's no way to climb outta here
要是你上臂力气再大一点就行了
Maybe if you had more upper-arm strength
没错  你应该要多多锻炼
Yeah, you should work out more
不如我现在就开始锻炼得了
Well, why don't I just start right now?
毕竟我现在在这就有俩傻子
After all, I got a couple of dumbbells right here
哑 铃
我听不懂
I don't get it
你能不能别靠得这么近
Would you not stand so close?
你要害我得幽闭恐惧症了
You're making me claustrophobic
圣诞老人
幽闭恐惧症是什么意思
What does claustrophobic mean?
意思就是他怕圣诞老人
It means he's afraid of Santa Claus
根本不是
No, it doesn't
住手  派大星
Stop it, Patrick
你会吓到人家的
you're scaring him
这样没用的  派大星
It's not working, Patrick
该死
Darn
章鱼哥  你踩到我脚上了
Squidward, You're standing on my foot
抱歉  海绵宝宝
Sorry, SpongeBob
你肘子碰到我排骨上了
And you got your elbow in my ribs
派大星
Patrick
也别踩我的土豆沙拉
And stop stepping in my potato salad
各位
Guys
别推我了  派大星
Stop pushing me, Patrick
你是说像这样吗
You mean like this?
不对  是这样
No, like this
你们不应该在这里打架
You shouldn't fight in here
这可是有魔法的地方
This is a magical place
派大星  从我身上下去
Patrick, get off of me
我跟你说过我有幽闭恐惧症
I told you I am claustrophobic
想得美  章鱼哥
Nice try, Squidward
可惜这里没有圣诞老人
but there's no Santa Claus here
派大星
Patrick
早安  海绵宝宝
Good morning, SpongeBob
来看看你收获如何
Let's see what you got
好重
Boy, it's heavy
肯定有好多的钱
Must be a lot of money
自由了
Free
我自由了
I'm free
章鱼哥
Squidward?
你在这下面干什么
What were you doing down there?
我可绝对不批加班费
I didn't approve any overtime
难道你是黑灯瞎火偷偷来这
Or were you sneaking here, in the dead of night
许霸王愿
for free wishes?
我唯一许的愿就是能离这远远的
The only thing I wish for is to be far away from here
特别特别
远远的
再见  章鱼哥
Bye, Squidward
一路走好
Enjoy your trip
运气真好
Lucky
那你昨晩赚到了多少钱
So how much money did you make last night?
我们没赚钱
We didn't get any money
不过我们找到了更好的东西
but we found something better
我们找到魔法了
We found the magic
什么了
The what?
我们在井里往深了挖  找到了魔法
We dug down deeper in the well and found the magic
所有的愿望都要实现了
Now all the wishes will come true
听好了  海绵宝宝
Listen closely, SpongeBob
现实中想要的东西不是许愿许出来的
You don't get what you want in life just by wishing for it
这到底是个什么玩意
What in the deep blue is that?
今晩会有满月出现
There's a full moon out tonight
你们喜欢我许愿要的望远镜吗
Do you like my new telescope I wished for?
真不错  珊迪
That's great, Sandy
许愿井真的好有用
That wishing well sure does work
巧合而已
Just a coincidence
觉得我的新赛船如何
What do you think of my new hotrod?
真是漂亮  泡芙老师
It's beautiful, Mrs. Puff
要不让我开一下兜兜风看看
How's about letting me take it for a spin?
不准兜
No
看见没  蟹老板
See, Mr. Krabs?
她那艘船是许愿许来的
She wished for that boat
意思就是那船是偷来的
You mean she stole that boat
早安  海绵宝宝蟹老板
Morning, SpongeBob, Krabs
天气真好
Beautiful day
这下你总能相信了吧
Is that proof enough for you?
休想骗我相信魔法
You'll never get me to believe in magic
休想
Never
证明给你看
Just to prove it to you
示范一下
I'll demonstrate
我希望我被人清蒸
I wish I was steamed
配以融化的黄油而食
and served with a side of melted butter
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs
不要
No
你说的魔法在哪呢
Well, where's your magic now?
我这是在哪
Where am I?
这是怎么回事
What's going on here?
完
我相信魔法了
I do believe in magic
不要
Oh, no